### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nxnson (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Scrum

Project Teams

**Problem Solving** 

## Languages

Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

## Certifications

Business Analysis Fundamentals

Customer Service: Managing Customer Expectations

The Business Intelligence Analyst Course 2022

### Honors-Awards

Impetus Award - SIM's Student Leadership Awards 2017

Fruit Embracer 2021

Fruit Embracer H1.2024

# Son Nguyen

Business Analyst at Chợ Tốt Ltd Company | A Carousell Company Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Summary

Currently as Business Analyst at Cho Tot Ltd Company.

As a graduate student majoring in Economics and Finance, RMIT University in Singapore, with my past experience in product management and a demonstrated history of working in Singapore. I am a resilient candidate that is willing to learn and adapt in any fast-paced work environment to bring out optimal solutions to generate increased business value.

# Experience

Chơ Tốt

**Business Analyst** 

August 2021 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

in Enterprise Field - B2B2C Solution. Connecting SMEs/Big Enterprises to value customers, especially in the Property industry.

#### Hoiana

Assistant To Human Resources Director (Hoiana Casino) January 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 7 months)

Vietnam

Managed by Suncity Group Holdings and VinaCapital, Hoiana is a USD 4 billion project and aims to create one of Asia's finest integrated resorts. This waterfront development features exquisite hospitality and gaming facilities, adding vibrancy to the region's long-established cultural legacy.

#### Main responsibilities:

- Assist the Director, HR&A with daily administrative duties and completes a broad variety of administrative tasks that include managing an active calendar of appointments; complete expense reports; compose and prepare correspondence; arrange transportation and detailed travel plans, itineraries and agendas and compile documents for meetings.

- Communicate with Department Heads and General staff on the Director's behalf and coordinates logistics with high-level meetings both internally and externally.
- Conduct research on prospective corporate, competitors to identify and evaluate current needs and assembles materials needed for the proposals.
- Proceed with mass recruitment program and execute the redundancy when needed.
- Support and evaluate to set up the SAP ERP system. (HRM and FRM)
- Perform other duties as assigned. (HR Project Management)

SD Enterprises and Trading Business Development Executive July 2019 - October 2019 (4 months) Singapore

- Developing new business via various lead generation channels.
- Management of all facets of the sales process, from lead generation through the sales process itself and into account management and development.
- Working with other internal departments to develop appropriate solutions in order to maximize sales success.
- Planning, preparing, and executing high-impact meetings with client prospects and potential partners.
- Maximizing revenue growth with existing accounts and our partner base.
- With networks and interest in developing the following markets: Singapore, Malaysia, and Vietnam.
- Knowledge of the local market.

Raffles Lifestyle Garden Pte Ltd Business Development Intern May 2019 - June 2019 (2 months) Singapore

- Managed inventory daily to ensure smooth operation.
- Coordinated with sales team to build and maintain close relationship with potential and existing clients.
- Supported technical customer service to address customers' concerns about company's products.

PHUNG HOANG SERVICE AND TRADING COMPANY LIMITED 9 months

Retail Sales Supervisor
July 2017 - December 2017 (6 months)

## Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Organize store operations and allocate responsibilities to personnel.
- Supervise and guide staff towards maximum performance.
- Prepare and control the store's budget aiming for minimum expenditure and efficiency.
- Monitor stock levels and purchases and ensure they stay within budget.
- Deal with complaints from customers to maintain the store's reputation.
- Inspect the areas in the store and resolve any issues that might arise.
- Plan and oversee in-store promotional events or displays.
- Keep abreast of market trends to determine the need for improvements in the store.
- Analyze sales and revenue reports and make forecasts.
- Ensure the store fulfils all legal health and safety guidelines.

Retail Salesperson April 2017 - July 2017 (4 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Education

**RMIT University** 

Bachelor of Business, Economics and Finance (2018 - 2019)

SIM Global Education

Diploma in Management Studies · (2015 - 2017)